# TERRENCE L. SMITH

Wailuku, HI + 619.307.1836 + <u>smithterrence509@hotmail.com</u> linkedin.com/in/smithterrence/ + https://terrysmith.github.io

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Highly motivated, with over 10+ years in the high-tech industry exhibiting excellent communication skills, strong work ethic, positive attitude, attention to detail, flexibility, flair for UI design, with an all-in compassing in-depth knowledge of web related technologies. Coupled with a proven ability to implement complex requirements into user-friendly features and functions excelling in independent and or team-based environments.

## **CORE COMPETENCIES**

- Application Development
- ◆ Front-End Development
- ◆ Full-Stack Development
- ♦ Object Oriented Design
- ◆ Domain-Driven Design
- Unit Testing
- Project Management
- Version Control
- ◆ Cloud Deployment
- ♦ Remote Development
- Business/Technical Requirements
- ◆ Agile/Kanban
- Benchmarking & Optimization
- Mentoring/Coaching/Training
- ◆ Web Development & Infrastructure

**Software:** JetBrains Rider, Visual Studio Code, SendGrid, Harusa, Visual Studio IDE, Node.JS, NPM, GitHub, Oracle SQL Developer IDE, Oracle Service Cloud – RightNow, LucidCharts, Photoshop, Lightroom, Sketch, Microsoft Azure, Google Analytics

**Languages:** F#, C#, Elmish MVU, JavaScript, jQuery, ES6, GraphQL, React JS / React Native, Vue.js, SASS, SQL, PHP, MVC/ASP.NET, Java, JSP, ZURB Foundation Framework, Bootstrap, Tailwind/Bulma HTML/HTML5/CSS/CSS3, XML

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# F# MVU Web Application Developer

Full Time/Remote

Hawaiian Telcom, Honolulu, HI

2022 - present

Specialized in developing F# MVU web applications with a focus on Domain-Driven Design, utilizing the SAFE Stack for both internal and customer-facing projects at Hawaiian Telcom. Demonstrated proficiency in crafting precise, concise, and easily readable code with minimal bugs.

- ◆ Engineered robust and scalable solutions by harnessing the power of the F# programming language, ensuring optimal performance.
- Implemented the Safe Stack framework, leveraging F#'s unique features to fortify internal applications with a steadfast emphasis on security and reliability.
- Seamlessly integrated Tailwind and/or Bulma CSS frameworks with F# to create visually appealing and responsive interfaces, showcasing a comprehensive understanding of the language's interoperability with UI frameworks.

## **ReactJS Web Application Developer**

2021 - 2022

Contract/Remote

## Brookbush Institute of Human Movement Science, New York, NY

Collaborate with stakeholders to gather business user interface requirements for an online Certified health fitness education and CE credits platform. Implementing these features and functions in an Agile/Scrum development environment using the following tech stack:

- React JS for client-side UI interaction GraphQL for data guery manipulations.
- Datocms for content sourcing, SendGrid for email campaigns and harusa for database SQL/Postgres and Heroku
  / GitHub deployments
- React Native / Typescript for IOS and Droid applications.

## .NET Application Developer

2019-2020

Contract/Remote

#### Decision Research Corporation Honolulu, Hi

Working remote as a contractor developer implementing custom client specific requirements for a MVC .net C# web application used in the insurance business for peril quote/policy calculations.

- ◆ Fullstack ms sql C# MVC .net development work from the FrontEnd to the BackEnd Implementing new E/R custom db tables for new features and data fields (Table indexing, performance tuning and Entity Object generating and deployment, sql scripts and store procedure development).
- ♦ API development to Import/Update Customer and Policy data saving 1000s of hours in data entry time
- ◆ Customer and Policy entry screens and Custom/Advanced UI Search and Client specific interfaces for Peril and Insurance quote calculations.
- ◆ Error Logging tools for data analysis Implemented error logging and Azure Cosmo data table solution for quick analysis of API importing/updating errors.

#### Front-End Web Developer

2013 - 2019

Full Time/Contract/Remote

Fanatics Inc., Boulder, CO / Wailuku, HI

Working remote on an Agile web development team developing responsive e-commerce MVC .net C# web application platform for all major professional sports leagues (NFL, MLB, NBA, NHL, NASCAR, PGA), major media brands (NBC Sports, CBS Sports, FOX Sports), and 500+ collegiate and professional teams.

#### ◆ Ecommerce Site Conversion:

Increased sales and over 200% ROI for the stakeholders by setting up an internal Node.js - JavaScript app to automate the process of converted not one or two sites a day but more than 50 a day to fully deployed production ready websites.

#### ♦ Feature Product Presentation:

Boosted sales 5%, per A/B testing results by implementing a new product feature presentation from design mocks to pixel perfect UI presentation - responsive across all browser desktop displays and mobile devices.

## ♦ Oracle Service Cloud – RightNow

As sole developer, set up and configured all ADA compliance help content presentations (MLB, NFL, NHL, NASCAR, NBA, MLS, partner sites) in an Oracle Service Cloud – RightNow desktop/mobile environment to flow seamlessly and sync with their leagues' ecommerce sites for site experience and order conversions – increase sale conversion by 10% across desktop and mobile.

## ◆ Internal Online Return Web Application:

Decreased return process time by 30% by working with the internal tools team to develop a new feature to an internal company MVC .net C# application to integrate product return functionality. This in turn eliminating the need for help desk agents to use a third-party site to process customer returns for online purchases.

## C# .NET Web Developer

2006 - 2013

**Full Time** 

Kore Technologies, San Diego, CA

Adapted Kore Technologies C# .net, web-based e-commerce business application to customer requirements, using client-side web technologies, object-oriented design and programming solutions, and IIS web application deployment.

- Developed and implemented new UI ecommerce features and functions.
- Setup automated testing solutions and as well as implementing innovative solutions.
- Wrote and developed technical specifications, as well as user guides for product installations and implementations.

#### **Early Career**

| Web Developer/Java programmer – Xifin, Inc. San Diego, CA                   | 1999 - 2006 |
|---|-------------|
| Senior Documentation Analyst – DataWorks Corporation (Epicor) San Diego, CA | 1996 - 1999 |
| Documentation Analyst - GDE Systems, Inc. San Diego, CA                     | 1988 - 1996 |

## **EDUCATION**

| Oregon Institute of Technology                | Klamath Falls, OR            |      |
|---|------------------------------|------|
| Bachelor of Science in Electronic Engineering | Technology (ABET accredited) | 1988 |
| University of California San Diego            | La Jolla, CA                 |      |

**Post-Degree Coursework**: FC#, ASP.NET, Java 1 & 2, Relational Database Engineering SQL, Project Management Essentials.

## **CERTIFICATIONS & AWARDS**

| Google Analytics Certification                            | 2019 |
|---|------|
| University of California San Diego Extension La Jolla, CA |      |
| Certificate in C#/.NET Programming                        | 2010 |
| Certificate in Web Publishing                             | 2000 |

## VOLUNTEER

| Maui Friends of the Library  | 2016 - present |
|------------------------------|----------------|
| Madi i fichas of the Library | 2010 - present |

#### REFERENCES

Available on request